We're going to call the word of this regular meeting of the Miami Special Utility Authority for today's date.
Second item on the agenda is an indication of our past year of new life, measuring, church, case, and college work.
Case, thanks for being here.
If you're having a here mayor and council members, let's about as much as we can.
Jesus, we just thankful that we've gathered today that we're blessed to have you here with us as well.
And thankful for your words and scripture that remind us time and time again that we'll just call upon your name and invite you to be our lives and in our lives.
You will provide guidance and direction in your help us Jesus.
And I know that as gifted as these council members are, there are so many things on this agenda and things that are sitting or facing Jesus where we just really need.
You have divine wisdom and guidance and direction and just, you know, we need your help.
And so I know that as we begin this meeting, by calling upon your name, that you will provide what's needed.
So I just pray that you just bless this meeting with your presence and pray that the things that need to get done, that you will get done.
And according to your will, Jesus, for it's in your name that we pray and ask all these things.
Amen.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America and to the Republic for which it stands.
One nation under God, the individual with liberty and justice for all of them.
Okay.
Adam 4 is public input on schedule personal charges with the audience, it was just to address the authority on any of the agenda items.
So being none, I don't find the consent agenda staff is recommending Adam 639 for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions, do we have a motion?
Motion to approve, right?
And a second.
One more.
All right.
Adam 10 update from the meeting staff since the meeting has been brought back in house.
And an introduction to staff.
Phil.
How do you feel?
I'm Phil Hill brand.
I'm the supervisor of the meeting services.
And I come here before you have been asked to give an update.
Well, first thing you do is start new meeting readers and give an update on how well our meeting has been done since we've taken it back.
And first, I'll introduce the meeting readers.
First one is Dakota Shek.
She's standing up.
Dakota is from Senika, but he's currently living in Miami.
He moved.
He graduated from Senika High School in 2014.
He was on the wrestling team.
And he's also.
He was on his senior year.
His football team made it to the state championship.
And they got to go to the Everdee Jones dome and play in the state championship.
He says a quite an experience of a lifetime.
up there playing in the olden being on the big screen and he had a busy February he just
recently found out his girlfriend at the time was pregnant and then about a week later they
got married so there's pectin their first child in the morning. Next we have Ryan Stags,
Ryan's from Carthage. He's lived there all his life. He graduated from Carthage Senior High in 2009.
He intended Crowder College for one year. He before us he worked for the Carthage R9 school district
for four and a half years because custodian and he's recently moved to the very southern end of
the japan which is cut his travel time in half so he can get here to work a lot quicker now and
on time. And he's obviously got a school fishing and camping and stalked in the lake and table
rock lake and beaver lake and he likes to travel and since especially these co-states.
Then our last one is Michael Longen, which you all know he's the son of our
emergency management director Glanda. He graduated away from my my my high school and more
majority of his life. He's lived my him. He's heavy into the crossroads church and he's
pronounced the audio video features and is always looking for new ideas and effects for the lighting
and he enjoys interacting with the citizens and takes pride in the city's metering services.
I'd like to introduce him to you all. And on the mean reading you know for two years we had
accurate here and it just wasn't working out you know there was a lot of problems with it.
I mean there's just it wasn't exactly one thing it was just numerous things. A lot of it was
the actual reading of the meters they wouldn't get done on time they were getting as you all know
in the past you know we had problems with you know estimating guys aside to once sat on their couch at home
and read meters which is a big no no. We the rereads were killing us there are Bill and
office were they were spending and these rereads you know if the reading is wrong when they first read it
you know the kicks out of its higher low wrong no kick out of reread. But with the rereads they were
actually we'd kick out the rereads and it was and I'll give you some numbers here in a minute. But we'd
send them back out to reread it and they'd come back with an even crazier number than what they had before
when they originally read it and then I'd have to actually go back out and reread it and get to
correct readings so that was spending our billing office spending anywhere from two to three days you know
getting the billing done and their problem was they were always running late and then we'd have to do
go through all these rereads it was running everything late you know bills were just barely getting done on time
taking lots of time lots of money and like I said she's taken two three days to do the
rereads and we'll give you some numbers here in a minute but now we have knocked that down with our readers
and getting everything done getting everything written.
on time, all the meters red, we've knocked it down to two or three hours that she spends in
the building, which is tremendous. And just numbers, the last five months accurate was here,
they've read up till about the middle of January, and August they had three hundred five rereads,
and just for the all four cycles. September they had three hundred four October they had two
hundred eighty nine, November they had two hundred thirty five, December they had three hundred sixty four,
January, and we honestly had January, the only red about half a month, and it was two hundred ninety-eight
rereads, which you know that also included rest in my three rereads. So that's unacceptable. I mean that's
you always want to try to have at least a half a percent or less per cycle, per reader, and that's
really low. This was like I said all the time we were spending, it was just they wouldn't
wouldn't right. Since we brought these guys on, and Michael, he actually was one of the very first
hiders of accurate when they come in here, and really he's only one, they really did a really good job
form, so that's why we had him come back. And so he's had experience and when we started taking it back
over in January, after just a few days with him, I realized that he's still new everything was everything
so we was able to send him out on his own, you know, he needed very little training, so that gave me time
or I could take the other two guys out, and just you know, do the month and tense training with him.
And I'm happy to say that the first February, the first reread bunch that was totally
them on their own after we trained him out of three thousand two hundred eighty nine reads, that's both
routes, all the reads. We only had 23 rereads, and of those 23 rereads, only 10 were
rereads and lungs of no read, and the no read with us now, it's usually a meter dead, a car part
on the water meter, you know, something like that that you really can't move. So that was an error percentage
of 0.32 percent, which is good. In February and cycle four, we had three thousand three hundred
eighty eight total reads, of those there was only 24 rereads, and only 12 of them were air reads,
which again was very good. And I mean you got to understand these guys the first month, two of them
first month on their own, and Michael, you know, he's had experience. So that's a 0.40 percent error percentage,
that's really good. This one's even better. In March, cycle one, 3,167 total reads,
there was only one error read, and three error reads with adjustments for a error percentage of 0.12
percent. You don't usually see percentages like this until you get read.
have four or five years of experience. And then the last one I'm going to give to you is March
cycle 2 and our 4,193 total reads at every stage of 0.46. So these guys already even though you know
two of them, first time they were at meters in their life, once had experience, they're doing reading
percentages of like I said readers have been here four or five years because we check back some of the
information we had on that and they're doing better and some of the guys we had before.
Customer satisfaction, you know with accurate, it was really getting bad. People were actually
locking their yards when they let us have access to meters. We're now they're back to opening
their yards back up for us. I actually had their get confronted daily by people just
ecstatic that we brought it back. I mean, they're just constantly. I even had when I was training
the two young guys, they even had the guy stopped the millerode and staring at us. I finally walked
over talk to him and he just says, you know, you all brought it back and I said, yeah, and he was just,
he's just happy. I mean he, he was really nice. So that was one thing we wanted to get our customer
satisfaction back because you know we worked for the customers, we need him happy and that also we need
accurate billing, you know we need accurate reads or billing is correct. It's cut down you know like
said the office time tremendously and the ladies done the billing in there which is what we want because
it costs as many and also won't give you an update on I-tron, you know, you all okay to new I-tron
hand-held readers in the software. Those supposed to be here sometime between the 11th and 22nd this month
and start bringing the new hand-held and it will be implementing those and with that like you've been
told before we will also be starting to have the availability where the readers can enter in coats and stuff
for code enforcement which you know they'll need to receive a little more training than what to look
out for and stuff on that. So that will help a lot. If you have a lot of thank you, I'd like
question is the numbers now compared to before I create that kind of line before I create took over
the nice parts of the way. Yes, yes, yes, in fact some under even lower and it's it's uh it just goes show that
you know one problem with that you read was they had terrible training and it's hard to supervise when
you're near supervisors over three hours away in Arkansas and on you know you all've been
busy people you know it's hard to supervise somebody lives in another state you know you can't
you know what they're doing all the time and with the training that they've received and the experience
already had uh we feel like they've been doing because me and Kevin said down and we actually thought
at the quickest maybe three months before we start seeing some results if not even longer and we have
effectively did this and just a little over a month we've got it down to I mean it's
they're doing the work of four or five year experience meter readers and for all of you and
can be and I'm really excited to hear about the new readers will be
here in the capability to enter those codes, because, you know, everybody all of us are part of
code compliance.
You have responsibility to report issues, and I know that's really going to make a lot
easier for you guys who specifically have that duty to get that extra helping in, so I know
that'll appreciate it.
Anything else to you?
I just want to say, you know, I don't like this when it's filled, Kevin, Jill, in coming
to me and saying, we can find a better way and we bring it to you and get your approval.
This is also just a good way to say thanks for trusting us, thanks for trusting staff
to another best way of doing this, and it benefits the city of IMA.
So we just thought you'd like to have this update, and that we've been able to do something
we think very good for the city.
Like I said, the customers have really been, they've really been almost ecstatic, you know, seeing
them when I was trying to mat there, and they still get it every day, just glad to see us
we got it back now.
Good, good deal.
Thanks, fellow.
Thank you.
Hi, I'm 11, this is New Business Day and the New Business.
Shout out to this agenda.
Say I have reports or any of the packet, and then you trust it to media announcements.
Item 14 is a term.
Do we have a most good journey?
Motion to adjourn.
Second.
Roll call.
Forster.
All right.
Let's take just a brief pause here before we start the council meeting.